

About me

Hi! I'm Giacomo. I am a software engineer in Bremen, Germany.

I have a bachelor degree in computer science and a PhD in mathematics. I enjoy both topics and like to work on challenging problems which also requires mathematical thinking. I have the mentality of a mathematician, which means I like to reason about the code I write and prove logically that it works correctly.

I have broad interests ranging from CAD, Machine Learning, optimization, scientific computing, 3D visualization and computational geometry, to web development, microservices and cloud computing.

I've been working on engineering software since 2012.

Technologies

6 C++ **©** C# **ASP.Net** CAD CAF CI/CD Docker Databases FFM **≫** Haskell HOOPS Communicator HOOPS Exchange Js JavaScript .Net **∆** Linux Machine Learning Optimization **Python** React & Redux Rust Scrum SQL TDD Ts TypeScript ▼Vue.JS WebAssembly

Experience

ELISE GmbH Software Engineer

Jan 2020 to now

At Elise I lead the *cloud services* team. In addition to the management tasks I also develop cloud microservices using C# with ASP.Net and Rust, together with their front ends with TypeScript and Vue.JS.

I also work on integration of *simulation* and *optimization* solvers in our C# application and on computational geometry algorithms in C++.

Contact Software GmbH Senior software engineer

Oct 2012 to Dec 2019

At Contact I was a developer of *PLM web applications*. I used Python for the backend and JavaScript with the React/Redux framework for the frontend.

I was the product owner of the products *3D Visualization, Variant management,* and *BOM/Virtual product.* I also managed the agile development processes for these products.

Contact Software GmbH Software engineer

Juli 2011 to Sep 2012 During my PhD at the university of Bremen I had a part time developer position at Contact. In this time I worked on the packages *KPI/metrics* and *Variant management* of the PLM software.

Universität Bremen

Wissentschaftlicher Mitarbeiter

Feb 2010 to Sep 2012

During my PhD I had a part time position as a research and teaching assistant (Wissentschaftlicher Mitarbeiter) at the mathematics department. I did some research related to my PhD thesis and teached exercise classes in algebra and topology.

Education

Universität Bremen PhD

2010 to 2012 *Summa cum Laude.*

I wrote my <u>PhD thesis</u> on the combinatorics and algebraic topology of toric arrangements at the mathematics department of the university of Bremen.

Università di Pisa Master degree in Mathematics

2006 to 2009 *110 cum Laude/110.*

Master degree in mathematics at the university of Pisa. I had a focus on abstract algebra and algebraic topology. My master thesis was about representation theory and hyperplane arrangements.

Università di Pisa Bachelor degree in Computer Science

2002 to 2006 *110 cum Laude/110.*

Bachelor degree in computer science at the university of Pisa. I had a focus on optimization and operational research. My bachelor thesis was about optimization methods for non differentiable convex problems.

Skills

Languages

ItalianNativeGermanFluentEnglishProficientDutchBasic

Personal

Interests Running, Swimming, Triathlon, Gardening, Slow food.